[Music]
hi my name is Brian nson I'm a program
manager in the business Central team and
in this session I will present you the
new and improved features we have in
financial
analytics the first thing and there's a
separate video for for how to install it
and start using it there are 14 new
powerbi reports for the finance area
through powerbi eded
reports there are 17 new templates five
rows 12 columns in the financial
reporting
module um we have Excel reports and we
have ad hoc analysis for fixed assets
specifically and we have a lot of new uh
learning resources stocks content for
the financial reporting area and for
analytics in general and then hopefully
soon in the second minor uh in this
release we will have new data to better
demonstrate some of these new reporting
capabilities but let's take a closer
look the first uh thing for analytics is
reporting and Reporting through powerbi
we have created six new apps uh one of
them for finance it contains 14 reports
which means pages in
powerbi uh they contain overview uh
Pages or or overview reports sort of
dashboard that you see here kpi pages
with uh a bit more detail and then it
also includes The Ledger entries so that
you from one of the the top reports can
drill through to The Ledger entries and
do validation or or further
investigation we also have templates for
financial reporting uh five row
definition which is basically the
reports like balance sheet and income
statement and we have a trial balance
with just a uh posting uh GL accounts
and then we have 12 uh predefined column
definitions that will allow you to mix
and match and create some new
reports we'll take a closer look and for
this we have uh new docs content that
will take you through not just the new
stuff but in general how to use the
financial reporting module to create
Financial reports and it will also guide
you through on how do you start from
your company creating some balance sheet
income statement cash flow and some of
the other reports including some tips
and tricks on how to do it best and most
easily uh so that you can maintain it
but let's let's take a closer look in
the product so I'm logged into my
business Central uh company the powerbi
report are found in the business manager
role Center in a separate uh embedded
action here where all of them
are are shown you can also search for
them in the role Explorer uh but let's
just take a look at the the different
reports there's a the first one is a
financial overview that gives you a at a
glance overview of of your data like
Revenue uh profit margin assets uh
vendors and whatnot and there is a
filter section so instead of getting it
all at least for the Revenue part you're
just looking at one fiscal year at a
time for example we can hide that
again there's
also um more interesting a balance
sheet and we can expand this one so you
can see it there's a lot of data if I
click on any of these values I can drill
through to the U balance sheet drill
through table
which is a separate report in here and I
can I can start looking at the
individual numbers so I don't have to
just look at some overview data and then
go to BC to to do verification or
further analysis I have it uh all in
this uh set of reports there are also
some reports that contain some uh
kpis there one for the the asset kpis
with a chart this is demo data so not
much has has happened here but you get
the the idea that with your own data you
not only get the ratio of the kpi but
you also get the different uh component
it is made up
of and lastly uh if you want to go
directly uh you can go to general ledger
entries uh to customer Ledger entries
and so
forth so a lot of uh new report a lot of
new data um that you can start digging
into through uh embedded
powerbi we also have um in the financial
reporting
module we have some new row
definition um and they will all no
matter localization have this uh code
balance sheet uh detailed balance sheets
summarized and the same for income
statement and probably at the bottom in
most localization a trial balance with
just a posting GL accounts if we look at
uh let's first take the detailed one we
can look up the report of course you
will see that it has a new row
definition it also has a a defined
column definition but if you look into
it you can see that there's this one
which is showing all 12 um months in uh
or periods in your fiscal year and then
there are uh further ones where you uh
compare to previous year's balances uh
you include a budget
um you compare year to dat or prior Year
year-to date or same period last year
there's there's these different uh 12
different um column definition that you
can combine with your report you can
either just combine it on the go uh and
then watch your
data uh or you can combine it and create
a new report and um and have it um as
defaulted uh in your system you can also
use the row and column definition to
create your own to modify them to add
more kpis or calculated columns um but
there's a set of a new set of uh
templates to start
with last release we started providing
Excel reports we provided nine reports
for the finance receivables and payables
area and we're continuing this work uh
covering more of the existing RLC
reports and this really is you have
three new reports for fixed assets and
one new report for
consolidation for fixed assets because
it's a separate little module we thought
that would be a good starting point to
um to do analysis based on a query for
the tables related to fixed assets it's
the fixed assets Ledger entries that is
the fact table in here with all the
related
table and that will enable you to to
start analyzing in fixed asset data
either to complement some of the reports
or do uh quick uh fact finding or
troubleshooting um when you need
it for all of this in the analytics mod
module there is a new Financial
analytics section in in the docs
content it is uh specifically about the
reports that we have it's about the new
financial reporting templates and how to
go about creating new reports in
financial reporting and it's about uh
the new powerbi reports they will have a
separate section for each of these uh
reports so there's plenty of new content
that you can dig into to learn about
these features but let's take a look in
the product for Excel reports in fixed
assets there are three reports the
analysis report that also cover the book
value report the projected value which
is sort of um projection of the coming
appreciations you it's a different uh
data set that you need to run and then
there are details uh for the fixed
assets it was one of the uh most used uh
reports let's look at one of the reports
we'll take the analysis report and
download it um to excel in the Excel
report you will first as usual get uh
something that looks like a report you
can either print it out you can modify
it a bit to suit your taste uh you have
the book value which was a separate
report uh in odlc and then you have your
data so you can start creating your own
reports if you don't like any of these
two um and the same with the the other
two reports it's a it's a way of getting
your data and start creating um reports
or doing analysis now that we are in
fixed assets we also uh created um a
query and it's called analyze fixed
assets or or let me just show you if you
search for it it's called a hoc
analysis fix assis at hoc analysis it
will open an
analysis view uh based on a query you
can see what is included in here there's
a lot of data
dimensions and um different dates
classes a lot of the tables from fix
asses are are now
combined and and you can start doing
your you can either create your own
reports or or start with um co-pilot to
assist you to create reports for example
this one would be an easy one to um
start troubleshooting if you're looking
for depreciations that didn't happen or
if you're looking for the acquisition
value and you can of course include more
but it's a good complement to the
existing reports because it's much
faster to do it on screen rather than
running a report in docs there are
there's more uh content on financial
reporting or doing analytics in the
finance area there's the overview of
financial
reports so you can see what are the
reports about and there will be more
content
provided uh if you
scr to the topic after um Finance
there's Financial
analytics which will tell you about how
you go about uh doing analytics and the
different ways of of running a report or
doing analytics in in BC and what tools
you have available ideas
for what is it that you will be looking
at uh and we also
have um a section on the financial
reporting
module uh how to set it up and what it
is that you need to to make it work for
you like there's some mapping to be done
and as you can see there is
for example this one and there will be
more uh chapters there'll be a walk
through on how do you start creating
your own report and how do you build the
the different uh row and column
definitions um so you can get started
here is a sort of a recipe for how to do
it so you you you're not stuck with a
with a blank sheet when you start
creating Financial reports and lastly
with all these new capabilities it is of
course
uh extra uh great if you can demo it in
a nice way with some data in it uh the
standard demo data in business Central
is mainly focused on showcasing the
different features so it has uh limited
set of entries because then you don't
get confused about all the data but can
focus on what does the feature do but
for the second minor in this release
we're going to provide three new demo
datas
sets one for financial reporting it will
have three years of data it will have a
budget uh it will have a breakdown in
dimensions and both uh balance sheet and
income statement are filled out so that
you can run both Excel reports and you
can run uh powerbi reports the embedded
reports uh with with a set of data that
makes sense that shows some Trends some
outliers but looks like uh real dat
rather than just partially 3 months of
data same for fixed assets it's mainly
the 10 assets we have but it will have
uh depreciation entries acquisition
entries of course and maintenance
Insurance entries just so you can get an
idea of what is it that you can uh do in
in reporting and for example use the new
analysis view on it there will be
reporting data reporting demo data for
project it's not showcasing how to use
projects but more uh if you're using
some of the embedded powerbi reports for
projects you will have data in it that
covers um an extensive period of time
and there will be some profitability
analysis on some assets that you can do
just so that you have data and can
demonstrate uh some of these embedded
powerbi reports and as we go we will add
um more demo data to Showcase reporting
because you really need a lot of data to
really demonstrate the strength of
powerbi reporting and also Excel
reporting with that I hope you uh dig
into some of the new features that we
have provided for financial analytics
thank you for watching